Come on,Joey!
乔伊，快说啦
I told you everything I knew last night.
我知道的部分昨晚都告诉你了
It's not that big a deal. So they're doing it.
摩妮卡和钱德搞在一起又怎样
I cannot believe you would say that!
你居然这么说
Sorry. Monica and Chandler are "making love."
抱歉 摩妮卡和钱德在“做爱”
No,I mean,come on. This is a huge deal!
不是啦，我是说这是大事耶
I need more details. Who initiated the first kiss?
我想知道细节 是谁先吻谁的？
I don't know.
不知
God,I just can't imagine Chandler being romantic.
我无法想像钱德浪漫的样子
Is he romantic with her?
他跟她在一起时浪漫吗？
I don't know.
不知
Are they in love?
他们相爱吗？
I don't know.
不知
You don't know anything.
你什么都不知道
I know one thing. What？
我知道一件事 什么事？
They did it right there.
他们在这张沙发上做过
The One With Chandler's Work Laugh
本集播出：“瑞秋知道了”
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
（中央咖啡馆）
Ross.
罗斯
Could I have a scone, please?
阿甘，给我一个英式松饼
-Want to hear some good news? -ls somebody else gonna give it to us?
想听好消息吗？ 有别人要说吗？
Because you certainly don't seem like you have any.
你不像有好消息的样子
No,I do. Someone I know is getting married.
不，我有 我认识的某人要结婚了
Weddings are happy occasions. Oh,it's my ex-wife,Emily!
婚礼是最开心的场合 对了，那人是我的前妻艾蜜莉
Sorry,man.
什么？ 怎么会这样
-Here's your scone. -Thanks.
你的英式松饼 谢谢
Stupid British snack food!
什么白痴英国点心！
Did they teach you that in anger management class?
那是情绪管理课教的吗？
You know what might help you deal with it? Think it this way.
我有个办法，你就这么想
You two are in the past. You can't be mad about the past.
你和艾蜜莉已经过去了 你不能对过去的事生气
Are you still mad about, you know, the Louisiana Purchase?
你还气我们跟法国买土地吗？
Nobody's mad about that.
菲比，没有人在气那个
Exactly! Because it's in the past.
没错，因为已经过去了
Anybody going to eat that?
那个有人要吃吗？
Look at us all dressed up for the party. What are we celebrating?
我们盛装参加公司宴会耶 是在庆祝什么？
We had a lot of liquor left over from Christmas.
圣诞晚会剩了不少酒
Our friends aren't here. We can be a real couple. We don't have to hide.
真好，这里没有我们的朋友 我们可以公开，不必躲躲藏藏
I know. I can do this.
没错，我可以这样
And I can do this.
而我可以这样
We can't do that.
我们不能那样
Hey,Bing!
宾
Who's the pretty lady, and what is she doing with you?
这位美女是谁 怎么跟你在一起？
I asked myself that very question,sir. This is Monica.
我也这样问自己 这是摩妮卡
My boss,Doug.
我上司道格
-This is Monica. -Hi.
道格，这是摩妮卡
-This is my wife,Kara. -Nice to meet you.
幸会 这是我老婆卡拉 很高兴认识你… 宾
Did you hear about the new law firm working for us?
公司找了新法律顾问公司 是吗？
Dickem,Stickem & Run.
杜塔、片达、豪伊事务所 （堵他，骗他，好耶）
Let's go drink our body weight.
我们去喝个痛快
What was that? What？
那是什么？ 什么？
That noise you made?
你刚才发出的声音
Oh,my work laugh.
那是我的工作笑
Your work laugh?
你的工作笑？
If you're going to survive this party, come up with one too.
相信我，想熬过这场派对 你也得编出一个来
All right. Check me out.
好，看我的 好
He says,"$30,Father. Same as in town."
…30块钱，跟城里一样
Everybody at work loved you last night.
昨晚公司的人都好喜欢你
And they like me more just because I was with you.
真的？ 而且他们因为你而更喜欢我
You repaired the damage from when they met Joey.
你弥补了不少乔伊造成的伤害
Doug wants to play tennis. He never talks to me outside of work.
道格还找我们打网球 他出了公司还没理过我
Except for that time at that strip club.
除了在脱衣舞夜总会那次
Strip church.
脱衣舞教堂
-I'll go find a racket. -I thought you had one.
我要去找一支球拍 你不是有一支？
I used to,but then Joey thought it'd be fun to go hit rocks...
后来被乔伊拿去中央公园 对着石头打…
...at bigger rocks.
大石头
Do you have a tennis racket?
瑞秋，你有网球拍吗？
I lent it to Joey,and I've never gotten it back.
我借给乔伊就没拿回来过
Good luck with that.
祝你好运
What's up?
你好吗？
Why are you here? I thought you had inventory.
你怎么来了？今天不是要盘点
I do,but I decided I'd take a long lunch...
没错，但我决定午休久一点
...and spend some time with my friend Monica.
陪陪我的朋友摩妮卡
You know,I feel like we don't talk anymore.
我们现在都不谈心了
How are you?
你好吗？
What is new with you?
有什么新变化？
Not much. Work's good.
不多，工作很顺利
We don't have to talk about work. Talk about anything.
我们不必聊工作 什么都可以聊
好吧…
You know what?
这样吧
Let's talk about relationships.
我们来聊感情的事
What's going on?
好，你最近怎样？
Nothing.
没人追
You go.
该你
There was this guy at the bank that I thought was cute.
我原本觉得银行有一个人很帅
But I don't anymore.
现在不觉得了
That's juicy.
真精彩
You know what? I actually do have a lot of work to do.
不过我确实很忙
You're sure there's just not anything else?
你确定没别的了？
I'm sure. Is there something you want to talk to me about?
确定，你有什么事想说吗？
No!
没有
If there was,I wouldn't tell you.
好吧，有也不告诉你
Then what happened?
好，然后呢？
You'll get your turn.
待会才轮到你
-Hey,Phoebe. What's going on? -Nothing.
菲比，在干什么？ 没什么
This is not over.
待会再继续
No,no,no!
糟糕 怎么了？
I was up all night writing this nasty letter to Emily.
我熬了一整晚写信骂艾蜜莉
It was perfect, and now it's all covered in....
原本写得很好，现在沾满了…
Actually,thanks!
谢了
All right! Ready to go to the movies?
可以去看电影了吗？
Actually,I think I'll skip it.
我想我不去了
Really?
你不去？
I'll read my book. I just want to be alone right now.
对，我要留下来看书 我现在只想静一静
Sure you don't want to?
你真的不去？
Tom Hanks,Meg Ryan. They get mail and stuff.
汤姆汉克斯，梅格莱恩 写信什么的
That's okay,Joe.
我还是不去了
Let's go, Phoebe.
好吧，菲比我们走
好恶
宾
Game!
赢了
I got to tell you,that partner of yours is a real tiger.
说真的，你的搭档真是快狠准
Are you all right?
你还好吗？
We'll just get a little sip of water.
我们喝口水
Am I on fire today or what?
我今天很猛吧？
Those birds are browned, basted and ready to be carved.
那两支肉鸡已经烤好 等着被切来吃了
Okay,easy,Martina.
别激动，网球名将
I think we should let them win the next game.
我觉得下一场应该让他们赢
I'm sorry,I don't understand what you just said.
对不起，你刚说的话我听不懂
Let them win one.
让他们赢一场
Are you crazy? We own those two. Look at them!
你疯了吗？他们任我们宰割
He can't even breathe, and she's popping pills.
你看他们 他喘不过气来，她在吃药
You're not giving them a chance.
你根本不给他们机会
They have rackets.
他们有球拍不是吗？
We'll make this the last game.
宾，我想打完这场就收了
Yes,sir. Put me out of my misery.
沤猓我求之不得
Are you sure you never played pro?
你真的没打过职业？
Please let them win.
拜托让他们赢
I'll take it down to 95%, but that's the best I can do.
我顶多只能把战力降到95%
-Missed it! -I got it!
糟糕，漏掉了 我来
Nice shot.
好球
I got it!
我来
Long!
出界
I can't believe you let them win.
你居然让他们赢
Well,at least you hid your feelings well about it.
至少你把不爽掩饰得很好
I was frustrated.
我很沮丧
It's my racket.
这是我的球拍
Frustrated with you!
是你让我沮丧
If we hadn't lost,they would never have invited us to dinner tomorrow.
如果没输那场球 他们也不会找我们明天去吃饭
What bothers me...
我最困扰的是
...is how different you act around them.
你在他们身边整个人都变了
The throwing the tennis games, the fake laugh...
故意输球，工作笑
...the "See you later,Bing!" "Not if I see you first,Doug!"
“回头见，宾” “不回头就不见”
Listen,I don't sound like some crazed, drunken pirate.
我哪有笑得像喝醉的海盗
I know you don't, but "work Chandler" does.
你没有，但工作的钱德有
I don't like work Chandler. The guy's a suck-up.
我不喜欢工作的钱德 那家伙是个狗腿
Because you said that...
因为你这些话
...I'm not putting out tonight!
我晚上不跟你玩了
Something's wrong. My brother doesn't stay out all night.
绝对有问题 我哥从来不彻夜不归
Maybe we should check the trash chute.
也许应该去看看垃圾槽
Ross couldn't fit down the trash chute.
罗斯挤不进垃圾槽
That's right. He almost could.
没错，就差那么一点点
Which is exactly how I got stuck there.
所以我之前卡住过
Oh,my God!
他回来了 天哪
Where the hell have you been?
你死哪去了？
Just,you know,out.
就是去外面了
Oh,out! God,I don't know why we didn't think to check there.
外面，天哪 我们怎么没去那里找
What were you doing?
你都在做什么？
I went to a bar,and then...
我先去喝酒，然后...
...I just walked around for a while.
...就随便走了走
You walked around all night in the city by yourself?
你整夜一个人在外面乱晃？
He hooked up!
他嘿咻了
He hooked up.
他跟某人嘿咻了
I don't have to answer your questions. I'm a big boy.
我不必回答你们的问题 我是个大人
I can do what I want.
爱怎样就怎样
He hooked up!
他嘿咻了
Tell us about her!
聊聊她嘛
Ross,you left your scarf
罗斯，你把围巾掉在…
Hey,you guys.
你们好
I know what you all are thinking, but Chandler is in Yemen.
好，我知道你们在想什么 但钱德在叶门
I'm a young woman. I have needs. I can't wait forever.
我还年轻，我有需求 我不能等一辈子
Yeah,that's what I was thinking.
我也是这么想的
So I'm asking you,please, just take a moment before you judge me.
所以我求求你们 在批评我之前先想一下
Nobody's judging you.
没有人在批评你
Mr. Right-place-at-the-right-time...
你，天时地利人和先生
...call me.
跟我联络
So I guess you finished your book.
看来你的书看完了
Had some time on our hands,did we?
有点闲是吧？
I know what you guys are going to say.
我知道你们要说什么…
You two would have very hairy children.
你们的孩子会毛茸茸的
I didn't know you'd say that.
我不知道你会说那个
Ross! Janice?
罗斯，珍妮丝耶？
All right. Hold on,hold on.
等一下…
This is Ross.
这是罗斯
He's our friend. He obviously went crazy.
他是我们的朋友 他显然是疯了
He obviously lost his mind.
脑筋秀逗了
Look,it's not that crazy. Okay?
没那么夸张，好吗？
But it's Janice! I mean,she's...
但是珍妮丝耶 她是…
...Janice!
...珍妮丝耶
How drunk were you?
你醉得太离谱了
Janice and I have a lot in common.
珍妮丝和我有很多共同点
We've both been divorced. We both have kids.
我们都离过婚，我们都有小孩
Are you going to see her again?
你真的要再见她？
-Don't put ideas in his head! -I will see her.
菲比，别影响他 我确实要再见她
Damn it,Phoebe!
你看啦
I have to tell you something that I've never admitted.
我要说出一件我没坦承过的事
In high school,I made out with James even though I knew you liked him.
高中时 我知道你喜欢詹姆法洛 但还是跟他上了床
That feels so good to get off my chest. Okay,you go.
哇，说出来的感觉真好 好，该你了
My turn? What are you talking about?
该我了？什么意思？
I know about you and Chandler.
摩妮卡，我知道你和钱德的事
I overheard you on the phone the other day.
什么？ 我那天听到你们在讲电话
You said, "I'll tell Rachel I'm doing laundry for a couple of hours."
你说“我会告诉瑞秋” “我要花两个小时洗衣服”
And he said, "Laundry? Is that my new nickname?"
他说“洗衣服？” “那是我的新绰号吗？”
And you said:
然后你说
"You know what your nickname is, Mr. Big."
“不是” “你明知你的绰号是大雕”
You're writing yourself a little play there,Rach.
原来你正在写剧本
Let me know how it turns out.
记得把结局告诉我
I wouldn't know,because I got so freaked out I hung up the phone.
我不知道 因为我吓到把电话挂掉了
Well,if you had kept listening...
如果你听完
...you would have heard me call him Mister...
你会听到我是叫他大…
...Bigot.
碉堡
Mr. Bigot.
什么？ 大碉堡
He tells the most racist jokes.
他喜欢讲碉堡的笑话
All right. So that's it.
好，所以就这样
There's nothing going on between you and Chandler?
你是说你和钱德之间没什么
Me and Chandler?
我和钱德？
Put your $20 down.
拿出20元来
First one to find the tasty treat wins,okay?
先找到零食的赢，好吗？
All right,let's get the contestants out of their isolation booths.
好，请参赛者从休息室出场
And they're off!
它们出场了
Get your foot off my contestant! Judge?
别挡住我的参赛者，裁判
Judge rules,no violation.
裁判判定没有违规
你们好
It's so weird to say this, but I just had a great date with Janice.
说也奇怪 我今天跟珍妮丝过得很开心
-What? -Are you serious?
什么？ 真的假的？
I opened up to her about all the stuff that's been happening to me.
没错，我跟她诉说近来的惨事
I mean,I talked for hours.
我说了好几个小时
It is amazing...
这种感觉真好
...to have someone give you such focused attention.
有人能专心听你倾诉
You don't need Janice for that. You've got us.
那你何必找她，你有我们
The duck gets the Nutter Butter!
鸭子找到花生酱饼干了 不
That's not a Nutter Butter. That's an old won ton!
那不是花生酱饼干 那是一颗馄饨
Judge rules...
裁判判定：
...Nutter Butter.
是花生酱饼干
Tough call.
真难判 是啊
Seriously,I strongly believe that we should support President Clinton...
但我们应该支持柯林顿总统
...and her husband,Bill.
和她的老公比尔
How do you like your coffee?
你们的咖啡要怎么上？
-None for me. -A little sugar.
我不要，谢谢 我要一点点糖
I'll have Monica stick her finger in it. That will sweeten it up.
那就让摩妮卡把指头伸进去 应该就会甜了
-That laugh doesn't give you a headache? -You get used to it.
你那样笑怎么不会头痛？ 久了就习惯了
I don't think that I can.
我不觉得我会习惯
This will be it for me on the work things.
我以后就不甩这套了
I laugh at my boss's jokes. What's the big deal?
老板说笑我就笑，这有什么吗
I'd rather not be with this work-weasel guy...
我干嘛要陪一个没尊严的马屁精
...when I can be with my boyfriend, who I actually respect.
如果能跟我尊敬的男友在一起
I got to apologize for Kara's coffee. I'd feel sorry for it in a fight.
我得为卡拉煮的咖啡道歉 如果它去打架
It's not strong enough to defend itself.
连自己都保护不了
Hear what I said?
你听到我的话了吗？
What?
什么？
It's a joke. What's the matter with you?
那个笑话啊，你是怎么了？
Well,I just didn't think it was funny,sir.
我只是觉得不好笑
Excuse me?
你说什么？
-Well,I just -Honey?
我只是… 亲爱的
I just don't think you understood the joke.
我觉得你没听懂
Really?
是吗？
I mean,it was really funny. I just don't think that you got it.
很好笑耶，你一定是没听懂
You see,Kara's coffee is weak-tasting.
卡拉煮的咖啡很稀
But what Doug did was imply that it was weak physically.
但道格是在暗示它很虚弱
-You get it now,honey? -I think I do!
现在你懂了吗？ 我懂了
-Thank you,Monica. -I thought you could use the help.
谢谢你 我觉得你需要解释
Coffee in a fight!
咖啡打架
You mind if I read my comic books in here?
瑞秋，我可以在这里看漫画吗
Sure. Why?
当然可以，怎么了？
Chandler and Monica are over there. It's kind of hard to concentrate.
钱德和摩妮卡在一起 我很难专心
She just called and said she was going to be working late.
什么？她刚打来说她要加班
She keeps lying to me.
她一直骗我
That's it! I'm going over there and confronting them right now.
够了，我现在就过去揭穿他们
Panty raid.
去找小裤裤！
All right,so you're telling me that I have to tell racist jokes now?
所以我得讲碉堡的笑话？
I'm just not very good at this.
对不起，我不太会圆谎
I'm a terrible liar. I hate having to lie to Rachel.
我很不会骗人 我又很讨厌骗瑞秋
-But we're not ready to tell yet. -I know.
但我们还不能公开 我知道，只是…
Ever since high school, Rachel was the one person that I told everything to.
从高中起我什么事都告诉瑞秋
I miss that so much now.
我好怀念那种感觉
She's my best friend.
她是我最要好的朋友
乔伊？
Oh,my God,Rachel!
天哪，瑞秋
What are you doing here?
你怎么跑来这里？
Well,I actually came over here to borrow this lamp...
我是…我来借这盏灯
...to look at my books.
好看书...
You know,see them a little better.
看得清楚一点
Okay,great.
太好了
Well,what I was doing in Chandler's room is that...
我在钱德的房间里是因为…
...I was cleaning it.
我在帮忙打扫
He pays me to clean it.
他付钱请我打扫
What a great way to make some extra pocket money.
真是个赚零用钱的好办法
When I said to you earlier that I was at work...
之前我说要加班
...I'm at my new work.
...是指我的新工作
Good enough. Right?
真不错，对吧？
I'll go look at my books.
好，那…我要去看书了
Go get back to my new job.
好，我得去忙我的新工作了
好
Congratulations on your new job!
恭喜你找到这份工作
Man,she is really gullible.
天哪，她可真好骗
-Here you go. -Thanks.
你们的咖啡 谢谢
-Actually,I should get going. -You're sure?
其实我该走了 你确定？
I can stay out as late as you want.
你想留多晚我都奉陪
I told you I'm on sabbatical from work
我说过我为什么休长假吧？
Yes,yes. You did.
对，你说过
-Oh,man! -What is wrong now?
又怎么了？
This isn't what I ordered.
我不是点的这个
Man! Can't anything go right in my life?
我的人生就不能顺利一点吗？
First,my marriage falls apart, and then
先是我的婚姻破裂，然后…
I know!
我知道！
You lose your apartment, you lose your job...
然后你被赶出你家 你的工作没了
...your ex-wife gets married so fast! And now the coffee!
你的前妻很快就再婚 现在咖啡又错了
-We need to talk. -Okay.
我们得谈一谈 好
-Sometimes I feel -No,no,don't.
有时我觉得… 不…
I'm going to talk.
是我要说
I believe...
我认为
...that the sun has set...
我们的美好时光
...on our day in the sun.
已经日落了
You're a very sweet person,Ross.
什么？ 你是个很好的人
Unfortunately...
只是...
...I just don't think I can take another second of you whining!
我没办法再听你哀下去了
Let me make sure I'm hearing this right.
我跟你确认一下
You're ending this with me because...
你要跟我结束 因为...
...I'm too whiny?
...我太会发牢骚？
So you're saying...
你是说
...I've become so whiny...
...我是这么地爱发牢骚...
...that l...
...我...
...annoy you...
...让你觉得很烦...
...Janice.
...珍妮丝…
Well,yeah!
没错
Oh,my God!
我…的…天哪
Will you be okay?
你不要紧吧？
I am now.
现在不要紧了
I guess that's two out of three...
已经两人出局了…
...Joey!
...乔伊
-Dude,we got to talk. -Okay.
我们得谈一谈 好
I wanted to tell you something before you heard it from someone else.
我只是想趁你听说之前告诉你
I hope this isn't too weird,but...
希望不会太奇怪
...I had a thing with Janice.
我最近跟珍妮丝交往过
You're not mad?
你不生气？
Why would I be mad?
我干嘛生气？
Because there's certain rules about this kind of stuff.
因为这种事有它的道义在
You don't fool around with your friends' ex-girlfriends...
不能追朋友的旧情人
...or possible girlfriends or girls they're related to.
心上人 或是有亲属关系的人
I am mad.
我很生气
But you know, I'm going to forgive you.
但是你知道吗？我要原谅你
Because that's what friends do.
因为那样才叫兄弟
They forgive their friends when they do everything you just said.
他们会原谅朋友 犯了你念的那串禁忌
Thank you.
谢谢
But I want you to remember...
不过我要你记住...
...that I forgave you.
...我原谅了你
I also want you to remember that I let you live here rent-free.
好 我还要你记住我免费收留你
All right.
好
And I want you to remember that I gave you...
我还要你记住我送你...
...twenty-seven dollars.
...27块钱
No strings attached!
无条件奉送
If you can't remember that...
要是你记不住
...we should write it down. Let's write it down!
我们应该写下来… 我们写下来吧